<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Experimental</string>

    <string name="IntroductionHeader">Introduction</string>

    <string name="TopicButton">Topics</string>

    <string name="MenuBackButton">Back</string>

    <string name="introduction_text">
        " This page contains the general information regarding the application's use and its contents.\n\n"

        "The general information contained in this  application are of trees found in the Philippines.\n\n"

        "The 'Topics' button situated by the top left should bring you to a screen with various topics that you may choose from.\n\n"

        "Each topic should redirect you to a screen with your selected topic and all relevant information  regarding your chosen topic."
    </string>

    <string name="action_settings">Settings</string>

    <string name="Tree1">BANI</string>

    <string name="Text1">
        "(Milletia pinnata; syn. Pongamia pinnata) A town in Pangasinan is named after the magnificent Bani."
        "While it is native in southern and eastern Asia, and Australia,"
        "Bani is also cultivated in Africa and the USA.A legume tree, Bani grows to about 15–25 meters in"
        "height with a large canopy spreading wide. It may be deciduous (sheds it leaves) for short periods."
        "It is often used as a windbreak or for shade due to the large canopy and showy fragrant flowers."
        "Bani's flowers are small clusters of white, purple and pink. The flowers are used"
        "by gardeners as compost for plants requiring rich nutrients. The wood is said to be beautifully"
        "grained but splits easily when cut thus relegating it to firewood, posts, and tool handles."
        "For thousands of years, its oil, known as pongamia oil, has been used as lamp oil, in soap making,"
        "and as a lubricant."
    </string>

    <string name="Tree2">ILANG-ILANG</string>

    <string name="Text2">
        "(Cananga odorata) Ilang-ilang originates in the Philippines, Indonesia, and Malaysia. It is a medium-sized tree"
        "reaching a height of up to 40 meters tall. When grown for perfume extraction, it is grown not"
        "more than three meters tall for easy collection of the flowers. The flower is drooping, long-stalked,"
        "with six narrow, greenish-yellow (rarely pink) petals, and produces a highly fragrant oil. It is often"
        "strung with sampaguita to make leis offered in religious ceremonies. The famous Chanel No. 5 uses"
        "extracts of the Ilang-ilang flowers."
    </string>

    <string name="Tree3">BANABA</string>

    <string name="Text3">
        "(Lagerstroemia speciosa) Banaba is native to tropical southern Asia. Known also as the Pride of India,"
        "It is also widely cultivated as an ornamental plant in tropical and subtropical areas."
        "The leaves of the Banaba and other parts are used widely in the Philippines, Taiwan, and Japan"
        "for tea preparation. Each flower has six white to purple petals and blooms only once in a year"
        "at the peak of summer. Banaba is also one of the 69 herbal plants promoted by the Department of Health (DOH)."
    </string>

    <string name="Tree4">MALABULAK</string>

    <string name="Text4">
        "(Bombax ceiba) Malabulak is often mistaken as the Fire Tree (Delonix regia) – originally from"
        "Madagascar – or the Caballero (Caesalpinia pulcherrima) – introduced from tropical"
        "America – because of its similarly vibrant red flowers. In Tagalog, it is also known as"
        "Buboi-gubat, and Taglinau. It closely resembles the Kapok (Ceiba pentandrum) which is an"
        "introduced species. Malabulak grows up to 25 meters. It sheds it leaves then gets covered"
        "in beautiful red flowers that attract lots of insects and birds. Malabulak usually blooms in February."
    </string>

</resources>
